Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Vice President for Business and Finance, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Vice President for Business and Finance, records
1949-1985
SC0068
Stanford University. Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance
19 Linear feet
Files, 1960-1967, which include correspondence, notes, memos and reports dealing with the Ford Foundation, the Plan of Action for a Challenging Era (PACE), Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital Center and the Stanford Children's Convalescent Hospital; and correspondence and patents, 1949-1959, pertaining to various electronic inventions; and the records of Rodney Adams, Director of Finance and Treasurer, 1976-85, pertaining to endowment funds, research and consulting, and administrative matters.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Kenneth Cuthbertson, Vice President for Finance, 1969.
Information about Access
Partially restricted: for more information contact the University Archivist.
Description of the Collection
Files, 1960-1967, which include correspondence, notes, memos and reports dealing with the Ford Foundation, the Plan of Action for a Challenging Era (PACE), Palo Alto-Stanford Hospital Center and the Stanford Children's Convalescent Hospital; and correspondence and patents, 1949-1959, pertaining to various electronic inventions; and the records of Rodney Adams, Director of Finance and Treasurer, 1976-85, pertaining to endowment funds, research and consulting, and administrative matters.
Access Terms
Adams, Rodney.; Cuthbertson, Kenneth M.; Ford Foundation; Stanford Children's Convalescent Hospital.; Stanford University. Office of the Vice President for Business and Finance; Universities and colleges--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Business management; Universities and colleges--Finance.
Collection Contents
- Original Accession, 1949-1967; Accession ARCH-1992-009
- Additional Material, 1976-1985; Accession ARCH-2003-301
  - Domestic Studies Fund- Deed of Gift, General [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Domestic Studies Fund- Deed of Gift, General [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Endowment Funds: Domestic Studies- Joanna Western Mills [1 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Endowment Funds: Domestic Studies- Joanna Western Mills [2 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Endowment Funds: Domestic Studies- Joanna Western Mills [3 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Endowment Funds: Domestic Studies- Management of Assets (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Endowment Funds: Domestic Studies- Van Deventer and Hock (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Background Publications from Other Institutions [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Background Publications from Other Institutions [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Gift Policy (General) [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Gift Policy (General) [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Pooled Income Fund (Regulations) [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Pooled Income Fund (Regulations) [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pooled Income Fund- Asset Reports 1983-1984 [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pooled Income Fund- Asset Reports 1983-1984 [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Endowment Funds: Life Income Funds- Tax-Exempt Securities, Municipal Bond Warehousing, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gift Annuities (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Endowment Funds: Metteer Trust- General (Current) [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Endowment Funds: Metteer Trust- General (Current) [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Endowment Funds: Metteer Trust- General (1978-1980) [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Endowment Funds: Metteer Trust- General (1978-1980) [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Endowment Funds: Montgomery- General (Current) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Endowment Funds: Pooled Income Trustee Participation (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pooled Income Fund- Asset Reports 1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Endowment Funds: Pooled Income Fund- Asset Reports 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Firms and Seminars (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Research and Consulting: Firms- Cambridge Associates, Inc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Firms- Callan Associates, Inc. [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Firms- Callan Associates, Inc. [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Firms- Dataquest (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Firms- Financial Research and Systems (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Q Group 1976 [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Q Group 1976 [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Seminars- Berkeley Program in Finance and Executive Programs [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Seminars- Berkeley Program in Finance and Executive Program [2 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Seminars- WACUBO Business Management Institute [1 of 2] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Seminars- WACUBO Business Management Institute [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- Listening Post [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- Listening Post [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- NACUBO Committee on Investments (Through 1977) [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- NACUBO Committee on Investments (Through 1977) [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- NACUBO Committee on Investments (Current) [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- NACUBO Committee on Investments (Current) [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Academy for Educational Development (Current) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Academy for Educational Development (Past) [1 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Academy for Educational Development (Past) [2 of 2] (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Funds: Endowment, General- Endowment Management Study [1 of 4] (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Funds: Endowment, General- Endowment Management Study [2 of 4] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Funds: Endowment, General- Endowment Management Study [3 of 4] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Funds: Endowment, General- Endowment Management Study [4 of 4] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges [1 of 3] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges [2 of 3] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Research and Consulting: General, Miscellaneous- Association of Government Boards of Universities and Colleges [3 of 3] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Listening Post (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Western Association of Venture Capitalists [1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Western Association of Venture Capitalists [2 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Administrative: University General- Articles, Memos. Etc. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Administrative: B and F Goals- Goals for Coming Year, Through 1979 [1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Administrative: B and F Goals- Goals for Coming Year, Through 1979 [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Administrative: University General- Internal Memoranda [1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Administrative: University General- Internal Memoranda [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Administrative: University Management- Management Devolvement Program (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Administrative: University, Board of Trustees- Board Simplifications [1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Administrative: University, Board of Trustees- Board Simplifications [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Affirmative Action Staff Planning Package, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Administrative: University, Policy- Affirmative Action [1 of 2] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Administrative: University, Policy- Affirmative Action [2 of 2] (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Administrative: B and F General Policy- Conflict of Interest Policy, Disclosure Statements (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Administrative: B and F Goals- Goals and Objectives (Current) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Administrative: B and F Miscellaneous- Requests for Publications/ General Inquiries (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Retreat, 1981-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Retreat, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Administrative: Department, Cash Management- Monthly Reports, Investment Summary (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Administrative: Department, Minerals/ Oil and Gas- General, Through 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Administrative: Department, Minerals/ Oil and Gas- Organization,Budget, Annual Report (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Administrative: Department, Minerals/ Oil and Gas- Advisors (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Administrative: Department, Minerals/ Oil and Gas- R.W. Thurston (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Funds, Non-Endowment: Petroleum Investments- General, Historical [1 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Funds, Non-Endowment: Petroleum Investments- General, Historical [2 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Funds, Non-Endowment: Petroleum Investments- General, Historical [3 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Funds, Non-Endowment: Petroleum Investments- General Current [1 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Funds, Non-Endowment: Petroleum Investments- General Current [2 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Administrative: Department, Risk Management- Risk Management Reports [1 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Administrative: Department, Risk Management- Risk Management Reports [2 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Administrative: Department, Risk Management- Risk Management Reports [3 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Administrative: Earthquake Risk (Box 8, Folder 10)